<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>osquery - Tag - t-lark.github.io</title>
        <link>https://t-lark.github.io/tags/osquery/</link>
        <description>osquery - Tag - t-lark.github.io</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 17:45:59 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://t-lark.github.io/tags/osquery/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Using Custom MDM Payloads for FleetDM Labels</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/using-custom-mdm-payloads-for-fleet-labels/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 17:45:59 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/using-custom-mdm-payloads-for-fleet-labels/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Programmatically Apply FleetDM Labels from Identity Data For a long time now it has been considered a &ldquo;bad practice,&rdquo; to join a macOS computer to any sort of directory service. Long have past the days of Binding to Active Directory, and the ancient lore of the golden (or magic) triangle is nearly lost in time, like tears in the rain. The one thing that we could consider missing from these days was the ability to locally query user and identity data through native tools like dscl in macOS.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>More Osquery Data Modeling in Snowflake</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/more-osquery-data-modeling-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 20:24:28 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/more-osquery-data-modeling-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Data Modeling osquery Data in Snowflake We have been working on many projects the past few months, and osquery data pipelines with the help of FleetDM has been one of our constant works in progress. Before I dive into the data modeling part, I wanted to share how we scaled this data out. We ended up going forward with FleetDM&rsquo;s SaaS offering over self-hosting the app. However, we are still streaming query results from FleetDM cloud to Snowflake over AWS Kinesis Firehose and we now have data streaming from FleetDM into Snowflake at a very fast rate and high volume.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Working with osquery Data in Snowflake</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/osquery-data-in-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 18:01:31 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/osquery-data-in-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I recently told my dog, Booms, all about how you can use osquery data in Snowflake. Needless to say, he was quite impressed with all the use cases and in-depth data you can model about your fleet of laptops using osquery data in Snowflake.
Booms came to the office with me, and he even got a bit of company swag! As we spent the day working I told him all about all the work my team was doing with osquery.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Snowflake Osquery Fleet Magic</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/snowflake-osquery-fleet-magic/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 17:07:04 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/snowflake-osquery-fleet-magic/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Snowflake, osquery and Fleet is Pure Magic! Many of you have probably heard of osquery, which is software you can install onto a computer that allows humans to query the OS to return fast and reliable system data. Osquery is not new, and many Organizations have been using it in various capacity for years now. Vendors and developers also ship osquery with their products these days as well. This allows a developer or vendor to collect local data fast and reliably for their software and solutions.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
