<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>t-lark.github.io</title>
        <link>https://t-lark.github.io/</link>
        <description>I have no idea what I am doing</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 18:20:44 -0800</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://t-lark.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Building an IT Engineering Team</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/building-it-eng-team/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 18:20:44 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/building-it-eng-team/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I started working in tech back in 1999. My first tech job was a repair technician at a computer store chain. I did hardware and software repairs, warranty repairs, OEM systems building, and similar support type work. Over the years I&rsquo;ve likely had a similar experience to most other workers in tech. I have had bad bosses, and good bosses. I also have worked with great people, and not-so-great people as well.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>IT Teams are also Security Teams</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/cpe-is-a-security-team/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 18:16:37 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/cpe-is-a-security-team/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[IT Teams are also Security Teams If you have worked in some tech related job odds are you have also worked with various security teams throughout your career. There has definitely been a divide between IT teams and Security teams I have observed in my near 25 years working in tech, but that doesn&rsquo;t have to be the case. During my career I have definitely observed security &ldquo;punting labor&rdquo; over the fence to IT teams, and I have seen IT teams dig their feet into the ground when security wants to change things.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>More Osquery Data Modeling in Snowflake</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/more-osquery-data-modeling-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 20:24:28 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/more-osquery-data-modeling-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Data Modeling osquery Data in Snowflake We have been working on many projects the past few months, and osquery data pipelines with the help of FleetDM has been one of our constant works in progress. Before I dive into the data modeling part, I wanted to share how we scaled this data out. We ended up going forward with FleetDM&rsquo;s SaaS offering over self-hosting the app. However, we are still streaming query results from FleetDM cloud to Snowflake over AWS Kinesis Firehose and we now have data streaming from FleetDM into Snowflake at a very fast rate and high volume.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Working with osquery Data in Snowflake</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/osquery-data-in-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 18:01:31 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/osquery-data-in-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I recently told my dog, Booms, all about how you can use osquery data in Snowflake. Needless to say, he was quite impressed with all the use cases and in-depth data you can model about your fleet of laptops using osquery data in Snowflake.
Booms came to the office with me, and he even got a bit of company swag! As we spent the day working I told him all about all the work my team was doing with osquery.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Servicenow Asset Data in Snowflake</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/servicenow-asset-data-in-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 18:49:24 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/servicenow-asset-data-in-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Inventory Asset data is extremely important to any organization. It is also some of the most difficult data to keep accurate and up-to-date. We have been shipping ServiceNow data to Snowflake here for a good while. Over the years the asset data has proven time after time to be extremely valuable. It helps filter out tons of noise and allows one to focus on specific asset data at any given time.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Diversifying Your IT Tools: Integrating Munki</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/diversifying-your-tools-munki/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 21:52:42 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/diversifying-your-tools-munki/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Hello Everyone, and it has been a while since my last blog post. I have been busy with work and with some other things outside of work as well. However, we did finally release Munki to our fleet last summer. This was a milestone project for us, and while we aren&rsquo;t the first Org to do this, I wanted to share with the community how and why we did this. Everything I will write here has probably already been done by many other Orgs that currently use Munki, and we aren&rsquo;t really doing much that is radically different.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Complete Asset Oversight with the Data Cloud</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/complete-asset-oversight-datacloud/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 21:48:09 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/complete-asset-oversight-datacloud/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Gain All the Insights You Never Had Asset and Inventory controls are difficult, and many Orgs spend tons of time and effort to try to solve problems around this very subject. In fact, they will hire humans, and spend lots of time and money to also get a hold of their inventory of assets. This problem is still very much difficult to solve, but the Data Cloud makes this problem at least solvable.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Data-Enabled: Post Nudge Campaign Results</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/data-enabled-nudge-results/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 18:11:46 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/data-enabled-nudge-results/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Data-Enabled: Post Nudge Campaign Results A lot of Organizations have adopted things like CIS Controls and part of those controls are around patching and vulnerability management. Depending on what version of the CIS controls you are using, this could be CIS 3 or CIS 7. This can already be confusing as the controls are very similar between versions but the have moved places in the CIS framework. One thing I think most tech and security professionals can agree upon, is that patching often to the latest operating systems is a great way to avoid your fleet of devices from being exploited.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Creating Data Enabled Culture</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/creating-data-enabled-culture/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 16:18:28 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/creating-data-enabled-culture/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Creating a Data-enabled Culture I think the term data-driven is common, and a lot of people are aware of the term. It also has a broad area of application across many practices. I feel my Org is already data-driven. We use data in all our metrics, planning, discussions, collaboration and more. However, today during a cross team meeting I realized that we are also a data-enabled organization. When the term popped into my head I thought maybe I was on to something new, or perhaps maybe something a bit esoteric.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Snowflake Osquery Fleet Magic</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/snowflake-osquery-fleet-magic/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 17:07:04 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/snowflake-osquery-fleet-magic/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Snowflake, osquery and Fleet is Pure Magic! Many of you have probably heard of osquery, which is software you can install onto a computer that allows humans to query the OS to return fast and reliable system data. Osquery is not new, and many Organizations have been using it in various capacity for years now. Vendors and developers also ship osquery with their products these days as well. This allows a developer or vendor to collect local data fast and reliably for their software and solutions.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
