<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>data - Category - t-lark.github.io</title>
        <link>https://t-lark.github.io/categories/data/</link>
        <description>data - Category - t-lark.github.io</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 18:01:31 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://t-lark.github.io/categories/data/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Working with osquery Data in Snowflake</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/osquery-data-in-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 18:01:31 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/osquery-data-in-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I recently told my dog, Booms, all about how you can use osquery data in Snowflake. Needless to say, he was quite impressed with all the use cases and in-depth data you can model about your fleet of laptops using osquery data in Snowflake.
Booms came to the office with me, and he even got a bit of company swag! As we spent the day working I told him all about all the work my team was doing with osquery.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Complete Asset Oversight with the Data Cloud</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/complete-asset-oversight-datacloud/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 21:48:09 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/complete-asset-oversight-datacloud/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Gain All the Insights You Never Had Asset and Inventory controls are difficult, and many Orgs spend tons of time and effort to try to solve problems around this very subject. In fact, they will hire humans, and spend lots of time and money to also get a hold of their inventory of assets. This problem is still very much difficult to solve, but the Data Cloud makes this problem at least solvable.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Creating Data Enabled Culture</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/creating-data-enabled-culture/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 16:18:28 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/creating-data-enabled-culture/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Creating a Data-enabled Culture I think the term data-driven is common, and a lot of people are aware of the term. It also has a broad area of application across many practices. I feel my Org is already data-driven. We use data in all our metrics, planning, discussions, collaboration and more. However, today during a cross team meeting I realized that we are also a data-enabled organization. When the term popped into my head I thought maybe I was on to something new, or perhaps maybe something a bit esoteric.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Snowflake Osquery Fleet Magic</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/snowflake-osquery-fleet-magic/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 17:07:04 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/snowflake-osquery-fleet-magic/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Snowflake, osquery and Fleet is Pure Magic! Many of you have probably heard of osquery, which is software you can install onto a computer that allows humans to query the OS to return fast and reliable system data. Osquery is not new, and many Organizations have been using it in various capacity for years now. Vendors and developers also ship osquery with their products these days as well. This allows a developer or vendor to collect local data fast and reliably for their software and solutions.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Post JNUC 2021</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/post-jnuc-2021/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 20:44:15 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/post-jnuc-2021/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[JNUC 2021 Recap Hello everyone, this will be a quick recap of my experience from the JNUC 2021 virtual conference, and a companion update to the talk I gave. First, I need to really thank Jamf for putting on a well produced virtual conference. I will admit that I was a bit skeptical of things like audio and video quality, participant interaction, and the look and feel of pre-recorded talks. Everything exceeded my expectations.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
