<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Data Apps - Tag - t-lark.github.io</title>
        <link>https://t-lark.github.io/tags/data-apps/</link>
        <description>Data Apps - Tag - t-lark.github.io</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 12:18:44 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://t-lark.github.io/tags/data-apps/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Managing Licensed Software with Data</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/managing_licensed_software/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 12:18:44 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/managing_licensed_software/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="turn-an-it-cost-center-into-an-it-cost-savings-center">Turn an IT Cost Center into an IT Cost Savings Center!</h2>
<p>So many times in my career I have heard IT/Ops teams be referred to as overhead. I have also heard IT being described as
&ldquo;just keeping the lights on,&rdquo; and all the adjacent things one can say similar to this. These type of statements has always
made me want to prove that IT isn&rsquo;t really just those type of things. I have always been trying to implement some sort of
cost savings where we can definitively decide where to cut costs. You never want to cut costs around things that have
a high positive impact. Since in many ways you do get what you pay for at times, and what you pay for may be very worth
it. So, IT is a cost savings center, a service provider, an enabler, an enhancer and much more than some of the
stereotypical things you might hear about how people perceive IT.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Building Endpoint Performance Metrics</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/building_endpoint_performance_metrics/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:35:46 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/building_endpoint_performance_metrics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Many organizations today still struggle with hardware refresh, right sizing hardware specs, and understanding the performance
impact of tools and software across their fleet of end user devices. This has been a problem since the beginning of humans
incorporating technology into their professional lives. In my 25+ year career I don&rsquo;t think I have ever had a job where
these problems were considered solved, and I don&rsquo;t think we ever got close to solving them. A major factor we have all faced
while trying to solve this problem is the lack of data compounded by the problem of being able to use and leverage the data
in a meaningful way.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
