<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Team Building - Tag - t-lark.github.io</title>
        <link>https://t-lark.github.io/tags/team-building/</link>
        <description>Team Building - Tag - t-lark.github.io</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 17:43:41 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://t-lark.github.io/tags/team-building/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Success Is Not Transitive</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/success-is-not-transitive/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 17:43:41 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/success-is-not-transitive/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="success-isnt-linear-nor-is-it-transitive">Success Isn&rsquo;t Linear, Nor is it Transitive</h1>
<p>With the climate of tech workers in a weird state post Covid-19 pandemic, and with the rise of the tech <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_celebrity" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">influencer</a>
I feel this topic is not only relevant, but also important. There are people who really want to break into a tech career
from their current path, and there are people who want to change careers within tech itself. Whether you are looking
to level up your existing career, make a move into a different section of tech, or just trying to break into the
tech industry any way you can, you have likely heard many other people tell their success stories.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Building an IT Engineering Team</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/building-it-eng-team/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 18:20:44 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/building-it-eng-team/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I started working in tech back in 1999. My first tech job was a repair technician at a computer store chain. I did
hardware and software repairs, warranty repairs, OEM systems building, and similar support type work. Over the years
I&rsquo;ve likely had a similar experience to most other workers in tech. I have had bad bosses, and good bosses. I  also
have worked with great people, and not-so-great people as well. I will say that I am lucky in the sense that most folks
I have worked with have generally been great, and the not-so-great experiences were very minimal.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
