<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>snowflake - Category - t-lark.github.io</title>
        <link>https://t-lark.github.io/categories/snowflake/</link>
        <description>snowflake - Category - t-lark.github.io</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 18:01:31 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://t-lark.github.io/categories/snowflake/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Working with osquery Data in Snowflake</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/osquery-data-in-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 18:01:31 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/osquery-data-in-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I recently told my dog, Booms, all about how you can use osquery data in Snowflake. Needless to say, he was quite impressed with all the use cases and in-depth data you can model about your fleet of laptops using osquery data in Snowflake.
Booms came to the office with me, and he even got a bit of company swag! As we spent the day working I told him all about all the work my team was doing with osquery.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Servicenow Asset Data in Snowflake</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/servicenow-asset-data-in-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 18:49:24 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/servicenow-asset-data-in-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Inventory Asset data is extremely important to any organization. It is also some of the most difficult data to keep accurate and up-to-date. We have been shipping ServiceNow data to Snowflake here for a good while. Over the years the asset data has proven time after time to be extremely valuable. It helps filter out tons of noise and allows one to focus on specific asset data at any given time.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Complete Asset Oversight with the Data Cloud</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/complete-asset-oversight-datacloud/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 21:48:09 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/complete-asset-oversight-datacloud/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Gain All the Insights You Never Had Asset and Inventory controls are difficult, and many Orgs spend tons of time and effort to try to solve problems around this very subject. In fact, they will hire humans, and spend lots of time and money to also get a hold of their inventory of assets. This problem is still very much difficult to solve, but the Data Cloud makes this problem at least solvable.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Snowflake Osquery Fleet Magic</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/snowflake-osquery-fleet-magic/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 17:07:04 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/snowflake-osquery-fleet-magic/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Snowflake, osquery and Fleet is Pure Magic! Many of you have probably heard of osquery, which is software you can install onto a computer that allows humans to query the OS to return fast and reliable system data. Osquery is not new, and many Organizations have been using it in various capacity for years now. Vendors and developers also ship osquery with their products these days as well. This allows a developer or vendor to collect local data fast and reliably for their software and solutions.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>IT &amp; Ops Data with Snowflake Part III</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/ops-data-snowflake-pt3/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 20:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/ops-data-snowflake-pt3/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Gain Oversight of your Asset Inventory with Snowflake Welcome to Part III of my mini blog series on being data driven with Snowflake. This post will be solely dedicated to how an organization can leverage a platform like Snowflake to improve their asset and inventory controls. Both Part I and Part II can be viewed with those links if you haven&rsquo;t read them yet. This post will focus on end user devices for the most part and not networking hardware, application catalogs, servers, and so forth.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>IT &amp; Ops Data with Snowflake Part II</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/ops-data-snowflake-pt2/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 20:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/ops-data-snowflake-pt2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Working with Data in Snowflake Welcome to Part II of my miniseries blog around Snowflake with IT &amp; Ops Data. If you have not read Part I, you may click that link to read it first. Data has always been very important, and Snowflake just makes using the data a ton easier than we have ever had before. This post will focus on some basic ways one can work with data with in Snowflake.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>IT &amp; Ops Data with Snowflake Part I</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/ops-data-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 20:00:08 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/ops-data-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Be Data Driven in IT/Ops with Snowflake Technology changes very fast, and it keeps getting bigger and more complex. We have so many systems these days, our systems have systems. It doesn&rsquo;t have to be complex and daunting to get reliable, and up-to-date data. Getting accurate data, while getting it fast, is key to developing data driven strategies. We no longer have to live in the constraints of capacity, limited storage, and limited scalability.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Shipping Jamf Webhooks with Fivetran</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/shipping-jamf-webhooks/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 21:27:27 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/shipping-jamf-webhooks/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Shipping Jamf Pro Webhooks to Snowflake Jamf Pro has a builtin feature where you have the ability to ship a webhook event when specific events happen in their application. This allows for a near real time feed of event based data which you can consume and leverage to gain insights about your fleet. Jamf provides some documentation online, found here.
Webhooks are generated automatically, and near instantly when an event occurs.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Data Sharing</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/data-sharing/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 19:45:03 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/data-sharing/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Data Sharing is Data Caring ❤️ I have come to the conclusion that there are essentially two types of people when it comes to data. The people that have data, and the people that wish they had the data. Another thought is that I would rather have the data and not need it versus need the data and not have it. For almost the past two years I have had the privilege to work for a great data platform company.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
