<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - t-lark.github.io</title>
        <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | t-lark.github.io</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 12:18:44 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://t-lark.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Managing Licensed Software with Data</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/managing_licensed_software/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 12:18:44 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/managing_licensed_software/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="turn-an-it-cost-center-into-an-it-cost-savings-center">Turn an IT Cost Center into an IT Cost Savings Center!</h2>
<p>So many times in my career I have heard IT/Ops teams be referred to as overhead. I have also heard IT being described as
&ldquo;just keeping the lights on,&rdquo; and all the adjacent things one can say similar to this. These type of statements has always
made me want to prove that IT isn&rsquo;t really just those type of things. I have always been trying to implement some sort of
cost savings where we can definitively decide where to cut costs. You never want to cut costs around things that have
a high positive impact. Since in many ways you do get what you pay for at times, and what you pay for may be very worth
it. So, IT is a cost savings center, a service provider, an enabler, an enhancer and much more than some of the
stereotypical things you might hear about how people perceive IT.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Building Endpoint Performance Metrics</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/building_endpoint_performance_metrics/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:35:46 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/building_endpoint_performance_metrics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Many organizations today still struggle with hardware refresh, right sizing hardware specs, and understanding the performance
impact of tools and software across their fleet of end user devices. This has been a problem since the beginning of humans
incorporating technology into their professional lives. In my 25+ year career I don&rsquo;t think I have ever had a job where
these problems were considered solved, and I don&rsquo;t think we ever got close to solving them. A major factor we have all faced
while trying to solve this problem is the lack of data compounded by the problem of being able to use and leverage the data
in a meaningful way.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Leveraging Application Usage Data From Munki</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/app-usage-data-munki-fleet-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 18:43:26 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/app-usage-data-munki-fleet-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<a class="lightgallery" href="/img/fleet_munki_snowflake.png" title="/img/fleet_munki_snowflake.png" data-thumbnail="/img/fleet_munki_snowflake.png">
        
    </a>
<h3 id="getting-application-usage-data-at-scale-with-munki">Getting Application Usage Data at Scale With Munki</h3>
<p><a href="https://github.com/munki/munki" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Munki</a> is a series of tools and a popular application state management tool many Mac Admins across the globe
use. Some out-of-box features of Munki solve problems many commercial MDMs still cannot solve to this day. It allows
a Mac Admin to write some declarative data and have Munki takes care of the rest for you. We use it to manage
and patch all of our third party apps in conjunction with <a href="https://github.com/autopkg/autopkg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">AutoPKG</a>.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Using Custom MDM Payloads for FleetDM Labels</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/using-custom-mdm-payloads-for-fleet-labels/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 17:45:59 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/using-custom-mdm-payloads-for-fleet-labels/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="programmatically-apply-fleetdm-labels-from-identity-data">Programmatically Apply FleetDM Labels from Identity Data</h1>
<p>For a long time now it has been considered a &ldquo;bad practice,&rdquo; to join a macOS computer to any sort of directory service.
Long have past the days of Binding to Active Directory, and the ancient lore of <a href="https://krypted.com/tag/magic-triangle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">the golden (or magic) triangle</a>
is nearly lost in time, like tears in the rain. The one thing that we could consider missing from these days was the
ability to locally query user and identity data through native tools like <code>dscl</code> in macOS. I have seen very clever
replacement solutions over the years to get this data down to a macOS end user devices across various enterprises, but
one thing has always bothered me about every method I have seen or sometimes used. The common theme was that they were all not very
security focused solutions. At a previous job, LDAP lookups were just straight up open to anyone on network, like it did
not have any authentication at all. When I was in vendor space I witnessed customers having various <code>curl</code> solutions
to grab that data from some system they could cache locally. Typically, these also were not very secure either.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Success Is Not Transitive</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/success-is-not-transitive/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 17:43:41 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/success-is-not-transitive/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="success-isnt-linear-nor-is-it-transitive">Success Isn&rsquo;t Linear, Nor is it Transitive</h1>
<p>With the climate of tech workers in a weird state post Covid-19 pandemic, and with the rise of the tech <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_celebrity" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">influencer</a>
I feel this topic is not only relevant, but also important. There are people who really want to break into a tech career
from their current path, and there are people who want to change careers within tech itself. Whether you are looking
to level up your existing career, make a move into a different section of tech, or just trying to break into the
tech industry any way you can, you have likely heard many other people tell their success stories.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Building an IT Engineering Team</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/building-it-eng-team/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 18:20:44 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/building-it-eng-team/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I started working in tech back in 1999. My first tech job was a repair technician at a computer store chain. I did
hardware and software repairs, warranty repairs, OEM systems building, and similar support type work. Over the years
I&rsquo;ve likely had a similar experience to most other workers in tech. I have had bad bosses, and good bosses. I  also
have worked with great people, and not-so-great people as well. I will say that I am lucky in the sense that most folks
I have worked with have generally been great, and the not-so-great experiences were very minimal.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>IT Teams are also Security Teams</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/cpe-is-a-security-team/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 18:16:37 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/cpe-is-a-security-team/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="it-teams-are-also-security-teams">IT Teams are also Security Teams</h1>
<p>If you have worked in some tech related job odds are you have also worked with various security teams throughout your career.
There has definitely been a divide between IT teams and Security teams I have observed in my near 25 years working in tech,
but that doesn&rsquo;t have to be the case. During my career I have definitely observed security &ldquo;punting labor&rdquo; over the fence
to IT teams, and I have seen IT teams dig their feet into the ground when security wants to change things. This is just the
wrong way to collaborate with IT and Security teams all together.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>More Osquery Data Modeling in Snowflake</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/more-osquery-data-modeling-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 20:24:28 -0800</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/more-osquery-data-modeling-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="data-modeling-osquery-data-in-snowflake">Data Modeling osquery Data in Snowflake</h1>
<p>We have been working on many projects the past few months, and osquery data pipelines with the help of <a href="https://fleetdm.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">FleetDM</a>
has been one of our constant works in progress. Before I dive into the data modeling part, I wanted to share how we scaled
this data out. We ended up going forward with FleetDM&rsquo;s SaaS offering over self-hosting the app. However, we are still
streaming query results from FleetDM cloud to Snowflake over <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/kinesis/data-firehose/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">AWS Kinesis Firehose</a> and
we now have data streaming from FleetDM into Snowflake at a very fast rate and high volume. We are typically collecting
data from osquery every hour on most things, and we have a lesser number of queries that run every 12 hours or once a
day.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Working with osquery Data in Snowflake</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/osquery-data-in-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 18:01:31 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/osquery-data-in-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I recently told my dog, Booms, all about how you can use osquery data in Snowflake. Needless to say, he was quite impressed
with all the use cases and in-depth data you can model about your fleet of laptops using osquery data in Snowflake.</p>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/img/booms-snow1.jpg" title="/img/booms-snow1.jpg" data-thumbnail="/img/booms-snow1.jpg">
        
    </a>
<blockquote>
<p>Booms came to the office with me, and he even got a bit of company swag! As we spent the day working I told him
all about all the work my team was doing with osquery. Anyone can see in this pic of him, he is very impressed
with the speed and scale one can leverage data from osquery in Snowflake</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Servicenow Asset Data in Snowflake</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/servicenow-asset-data-in-snowflake/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 18:49:24 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/servicenow-asset-data-in-snowflake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Inventory Asset data is extremely important to any organization. It is also some of the most difficult data to keep
accurate and up-to-date. We have been shipping ServiceNow data to Snowflake here for a good while. Over the years the asset data
has proven time after time to be extremely valuable. It helps filter out tons of noise and allows one to focus on
specific asset data at any given time. Just by creating some simple queries and joining ServiceNow data with other data
sources. I recently created a new <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/views-introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">view</a> in Snowflake to help us better filter data down to more specifics.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
