<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Open Source - Tag - t-lark.github.io</title>
        <link>https://t-lark.github.io/tags/open-source/</link>
        <description>Open Source - Tag - t-lark.github.io</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 21:52:42 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://t-lark.github.io/tags/open-source/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Diversifying Your IT Tools: Integrating Munki</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/diversifying-your-tools-munki/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 21:52:42 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/diversifying-your-tools-munki/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone, and it has been a while since my last blog post. I have been busy with work and with some other things
outside of work as well. However, we did finally release Munki to our fleet last summer. This was a milestone project for us, and
while we aren&rsquo;t the first Org to do this, I wanted to share with the community how and why we did this. Everything I will
write here has probably already been done by many other Orgs that currently use Munki, and we aren&rsquo;t really doing much
that is radically different. So, if you hae deployed a server-less Munki setup before, this is probably not going to be
new to you. That being said, <code>server-less</code> is a pretty key word for our vision here.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Data-Enabled: Post Nudge Campaign Results</title>
    <link>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/data-enabled-nudge-results/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 18:11:46 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>tlark</author>
    <guid>https://t-lark.github.io/posts/data-enabled-nudge-results/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h3 id="data-enabled-post-nudge-campaign-results">Data-Enabled: Post Nudge Campaign Results</h3>
<p>A lot of Organizations have adopted things like <a href="https://www.cisecurity.org/controls" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">CIS Controls</a> and part of those
controls are around patching and vulnerability management. Depending on what version of the CIS controls you are using, this
could be <a href="https://www.cisecurity.org/controls/cis-controls-navigator/?version=7" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">CIS 3</a> or <a href="https://www.cisecurity.org/controls/cis-controls-navigator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">CIS 7</a>.
This can already be confusing as the controls are very similar between versions but the have moved places in the CIS
framework. One thing I think most tech and security professionals can agree upon, is that patching often to the latest
operating systems is a great way to avoid your fleet of devices from being exploited. Known vulnerabilities have a shelf life,
and bad actors know that some organizations do not patch, or patch extremely slow. So, they develop attacks against
known published vulnerabilities.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
